virtuallove.ie 2012-04-23

# VirtualLove.ie find your match today!

Privacy policy

This website is owned and operated by VirtualLove.ie | Easy Finder Group, Office 2, Beechfied Avenue, Dublin. 

VirtualLove.ie has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your right to privacy and data protection. We handle all our information gathering and dissemination procedures with every reasonable safeguard for your protection.

We confirm that all personal data handled and stored by us is done so in strict compliance with the EU Data Protection Rules. 

This allows you to understand how your data is being protected. 

What information do we process?

We collect the information set out below from you during the registration process and your use of the VirtualLove.ie service. By submitting this information (including sensitive personal information), you are explicitly agreeing to us processing that information in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Please remember that due to the nature of the VirtualLove.ie service, any information that is disclosed to VirtualLove.ie, except the guarantees of privacy that are stated below, can become public information. You should therefore exercise caution when disclosing personal information. 

On registration with the website

On initial registration we collect personal information such as your name, date of birth, e-mail address and postal address. We use this information for administrative purposes and to provide you with the VirtualLove.ie service. So for example, we use your e-mail address to send you our newsletters and special offers (if you have chosen to receive them) and we use some of this information to help create your profile. For further information on how we use this information (in a non-identifiable way) for your profile, please see below. 

My Profile:

To allow other registered users to be able to view a profile about you VirtualLove.ie creates one from a combination of the registration data and personality test results in the My Profile section, which has links to the part of our service where you can upload photographs of yourself. You are also given the opportunity to change the description of yourself. We use the information you provide about your personal preferences (collated on registration and in the My Profile section) to help match you to a potential partner. Some of this information will be visible by other members, such as age, marital status, height, region, occupation etc. Your name, email address, home address and other specific 'identifier' data will NOT be visible to other users. Please remember that you can choose to delete or hide your profile at any time by selecting the relevant option in the 'My VirtualLove.ie/Data & Settings' section of the website. 

Communicate with other registered members via the website

If you have registered with the website, we provide a means by which you can communicate with other registered members of the website. We do not use the information disclosed during these communications for any purpose. 

Cookies and log files: 

While on our website, we automatically log certain information about how you are using the website. For example, we use your IP internet address to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our website, and to help identify you for our own administrative purposes.

We also use a feature known as a cookie. A cookie is a small data file which resides on your computer which allows us to recognise you as a user when you return to website using the same computer and web browser. Cookies allow us to keep track of your chosen set-up of the website. We also use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, to save your password so you that don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our website, and for other purposes.

Most browsers are set up to accept cookies, but you can configure your browser to refuse cookies or to notify you when you have received one. If you want to stop cookies being stored on your computer in future, please refer to your browser manufacturer's instructions by clicking "Help" in your browser menu. Further information on deleting or controlling cookies is available at www.allaboutcookies.org. Please be aware that disabling cookies will stop your ability to enter our website.

Information sharing and disclosure: 

We do not generally disclose personal information we have collected from you through this website to third parties. We may however disclose the information that we have collated to the following:

If you register as a member

Information that you disclose to us may be disclosed to employees and agents of VirtualLove.ie for them to administer your account and the gay-VirtualLove.ie service.

Our users

If you are a registered user, you are publicly identified on the website by an anonymous number code; your user name is not visible to other VirtualLove.ie members. The information that you provide in your profile is, however, available to the website's members. Similarly, if you choose to reveal any other personal information in any communications with another registered member, that information will of course, be available to such member.

Co-branded sites

Sometimes we enter into promotional arrangements with carefully selected partners where we operate a website branded with both our and their branding. We call this a co-branded site. If you registered as a member through a co-branded site, then we will share the information that you disclose on registration (but no other information) with that co-branding partner. Please check their privacy policy to see how they will use your information. We will give you details of how to access their privacy policy when you first register.

Transfer

If ownership or operational control of all or part of this website is transferred, your information may be disclosed to a transferee, but we would require them to use that information in a way that is consistent with this Privacy Statement.

Newsletter unsubscribe:

You can choose to remove yourself from our mailing list at any time, in the 'My VirtualLove.ie/Data & Settings section of the website. 

Editing your information:

You can access and edit any information you have previously entered by selecting the 'My VirtualLove.ie/Data & Settings' section of the website. You can also deselect Email notification of further contact matches. 

Changes:

Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this page so that you are always aware of the information that we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. 

Contacting VirtualLove.ie:

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, about navigating the website, or about the services that VirtualLove.ie offers, please do not hesitate to contact:

Administration
